JONATHAN FELIX YASHIM

Address: 8 NITEL Quarters, Kaduna, Nigeria

Phone Number: 08038077440

Email: mailto:jonathan_felix_yashim@yahoo.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonathan-felix-yashim
Github https://github.com/JFYashim/Portfolio projects

ABOUT

I am a highly motivated and detailed oriented professional with a strong agricultural background and vast knowledge in agricultural science, economics, statistics and research. Also complemented by courses in Python, Data Analytics from Cisco Networking Academy and also a certificate course in machine learning from Alison academy. I utilize my proficiency in Data analysis, Relational databases management and machine learning techniques to drive growth and sustainability in any growth oriented organization.

EDUCATION

B.Sc. Agriculture Ahmadu Bello University, 2005 - 2010

Zaria, Nigeria

Relevant Course Work

- Statistical Analysis and Experimental Design
- Agricultural Economics and Policy
- Data Analysis and Interpretation
- Research Methods in Agriculture
- Computer Applications in Agriculture
- Quantitative Methods in Agriculture

CERTIFICATION

Data Analytics Essentials

CISCO Networking Academy
2024
Python Essential 1

CISCO Networking Academy
2024
Machine Learning in Python

Alison
2024

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- 1. Programming languages: Python, R,SQL
- 2. Database management: MySQL
- 3. Data analysis libraries: Pandas, Numpy, Seaborn, Matplotlib, Scikit-learn, Scipy
- 4. Data visualization tools: Tableau
- 5. Machine learning algorithms: Supervised/Unsupervised learning, Regression, Classification
- 6. Operating Systems: Windows

EXPERIENCE

Kutunban Limited (Data Analyst)

2015 - 2024

Key Responsibilities

- Data collection and analysis
- Machine learning model development and deployment

- Data-driven decision making
- Problem-solving and critical thinking
- Statistical modeling and interpretation
- Data visualization and communication
- Problem-solving and critical thinking
- Research and reporting

Capital FOREX (Technical Analyst)

2013 - 2015

Key Responsibilities

- Market analysis and forecasting
- Charting and technical indicator development
- Trading strategy development and refinement
- Risk management and recommendation
- Market research and staying up-to-date with market news
- Communication and presentation of analysis and recommendations

- Data analysis and tool development

PROJECTS

Topics Technologies

An Exploratory Analysis of Road Traffic Crashes in Nigeria: MySQL

Trends, Patterns, and Correlations.

Breast Cancer Diagnostic Dataset Classification Pandas, Scikit-Learn

Comprehensive Analysis of Customer Shopping Trends MySQL

Prevalence of Mental Health Disorders by Country Visual Pandas, Seaborn, Matplotlib

analysis.

Car Sales Prediction and Analysis Scikit Learn, Pandas, Numpy

Covid19 Africa Visual Analysis Tableau

REFERENCE

Josephine Karen Ibrahim Kutunban Limited 08060034375